OBIORA UKWUANI

WEB DEVELOPER

OBJECTIVE

Web Developer with good experience in designing and developing user friendly interfaces, testing and debugging, and good in team work and ready to contribute in the achievement of company goals. Proven ability in optimizing web functionalities that improve data retrieval and workflow efficiencies.

EXPERIENCE

2022 – Present | Africa Mental Health Reform Consortium(AMHEC) **Web Developer**

- Built from scratch a website, showing the caring movement being undertaken by AMHEC in ensuring mental health in Africa.
- Worked in a team.
- Gave feedback at each point in the website development, and debugging was done regularly.

2016 – Present | Dave Computers and KC Gaming Agents' Outlet Damaturu

Networking and Software Installations Manager

- Checks and ensures that all network connections; ports, hubs and USB are functioning properly; and also ensures that wireless network connections are all transmitting well.
- Oversees that all online and offline file sharing between computers are accessible and functioning as it should.
- Applies useful standards, policies and regulatory guidelines to promote and provide a conducive working environment.
- Devotes special emphasis to punctuality and works to maintain outstanding attendance record.

2021 – Present | Web Development Projects for Students' (Students' Final Defence Programs)

Web Developer

CONTACT



08131907599



obioraukwuani@gmail.com



easyappx.github.io/portfolio/



Behind Lale Guest Inn New Jerusalem Damaturu 620101 Yobe States

SKILLS

- HTML / CSS / JavaScript
- JQuery / AJAX / Angular JS
- ASP / SQL / JavaScript
- Visual Basic / JAVA
- PHP / MySQL
- WordPress / Bootstrap
- ISON / GitHUB
- MS Word / MS Excel
- MS PowerPoint
- Networking

COMPETENCIES

- Web Development Projects
- Website Design Using HTML & CSS
- Web Page Programming / Programming
- Project Forecasting
- Site Template Development
- Responsive Web Design
- Search Engine Optimization
- Troubleshooting / Debugging

- Uses critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate possible solutions and make decisions.
- Built responsive web based platforms / systems for students from scratch for their final defence program.
- Learn new skills and apply them to daily tasks of web development to improve efficiency and productivity.

2020 – 2021 | Goziconarc Buildings Abakaliki (Private Enterprise) **Web Developer**

- Planned website development from scratch; designed and sketched samples of the website
- Designed and developed user-friendly and responsive website that allows users to explore through a series of building adverts for clients.
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed
- Coded website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP languages

2021 – 2021 | Ebonyi State University; Nacos Website Design and Development

NACOS (National Association of Computing Students) Web **Development Associate** (Ebonyi State University Chapter)

- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.
- Improved design operations through consistent hard work and dedication.
- Contributed to development of a standard website for 2017/2018 Nacos chapter for computer science students.
- Completed paperwork, recognizing discrepancies and addressing for resolution.

EDUCATION

2017 – 2022 | Ebonyi State University Abakaliki – Abakaliki Ebonyi State Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

2004 – 2010 | Sacred Heart Seminary – Nsude Enugu State Senior School Certificate Examination: SSCE

2010 – 2011 | Pope John Paul II Major Seminary – Akwa Anambra State Latin Diploma: Latin

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hausa
- Igbo

1999 – 2004 | St. Peters' Academy – Potiskum Yobe State

CERTIFICATIONS | COURSES | TRAINING

2022 – 2022 | Udemy: Instructors; Codestars Rob Percival & Nick Walter

Complete Android Oreo Developer Course, Java - Build 23 Apps

2021 – 2022 | Udemy: Instructors; George Levy

Cryptocurrency Fundamentals: Buy, Sell, Trade Cryptocurrency

2014 – 2015 | Pax Herbal Clinic Laboratory – Ohum Monastery Benin State

Pax Practitioner / Agent

2015 | Green-White Technologies LTd.

Business Ideas and Entrepreneurship Skills

2013 | DELES Programme Nigeria: Development Education and Leadership Services

DELES Leadership & Human Development

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Work for African Mental Health Reform Consortium (AMHEC); joined the team in developing a responsive website promoting mental health in Africa; Web Developer (WordPress).
- Collaborated with a team of nine developers in the development of a website for NACOS, Ebonyi State University Chapter; Computer Science Department.
- Used Microsoft Excel to develop an inventory tracking spreadsheets, which was later imported to a Record Keeping System built with HTML CSS and PHP for a client.